<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erick Rudelman</title>
    <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erick Rudelman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 11:01:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Breast Cancer Detection App</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 11:01:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_1/</guid>
      <description>The provided Python code showcases an interactive web application built using the Streamlit library. This application serves a significant purpose in breast cancer prediction and data visualization. It combines elements of machine learning, data visualization, and user interaction to provide valuable insights into breast cancer data.
Breast Cancer Prediction and Data Visualization App
Function and Purpose: This Streamlit app serves as a versatile tool to predict whether a given tumor is malignant or benign based on user-input tumor parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter II: Analyzing EPL Player Stats</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_2/</guid>
      <description>Function and Purpose: This Streamlit app provides an engaging platform to explore and analyze English Premier League (EPL) player statistics for the 2021/2022 season. It empowers users to visualize and understand player performance, correlations between different stats, and team-related insights. The app facilitates data-driven decision-making for football enthusiasts, sports analysts, and EPL fans.
App Workflow and Features:
Sidebar User Input: The sidebar allows users to interactively select clubs (teams) using a multiselect dropdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter III: Disney Movies Web Scraping</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_3/</guid>
      <description>The provided code is a Python script that performs web scraping to gather information about Disney movies from Wikipedia. It utilizes libraries like beautifulsoup4 and requests to extract and process data from HTML web pages.
The script effectively scrapes Wikipedia pages, extracts movie information, and enhances the data by fetching additional details from external sources. It then saves the enriched data in different formats for further analysis or display.
TASK 1:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project IV: DNA Nucleotide Count Web App</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_4/</guid>
      <description>The DNA Nucleotide Count and Analysis Web App is designed as a versatile tool for analyzing DNA sequences, offering functions to count nucleotides, compute reverse complements, find open reading frames (ORFs), and translate DNA into protein sequences. This Streamlit app empowers users to explore DNA-related insights and conduct basic genetic analyses.
The app workflow and its various features can be outlined as follows:
The app starts by displaying an image of a DNA logo and its title, introducing its purpose and functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project V: Simple Stock Price App</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_5/</guid>
      <description>The Simple Stock Price App is a streamlined application built using Streamlit and Yahoo Finance (yfinance) to display historical stock data of Google (GOOGL). The app aims to present the closing price and volume of Google&amp;rsquo;s stock in an easily accessible and visually informative manner.
When you run the app, it generates the following features:
A bold title that introduces the app as the &amp;ldquo;Simple Stock Price App.&amp;rdquo;
The stock data visualization: The app showcases two line charts that display the closing price and volume of Google&amp;rsquo;s stock over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project VI: Winning Space Race With Data Science</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/project_6/</guid>
      <description>Project background and context
SpaceX is the only private company to ever return a spacecraft from low-earth orbit. This is due to their capability to reuse the first stage of their rocket. For SpaceX, rocket launches are relatively inexpensive. For this project, data science techniques are applied in order to build a pipeline and determine meaningful insights if another company wants to compete against Space X.
Relevant data will be obtained to predict outcomes such as: • Price of launch • If first stage will land successfully or not</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: erickrudi@hotmail.com
WhatsApp: +(506) 8991-0020
Platform URL LinkedIn Erick&amp;rsquo;s LinkedIn Profile GitHub Erick&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Profile Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erick</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m an explorer at heart, with a background in Mechanical Engineering from the University of New South Wales and Industrial Engineer at ULACIT. Along the way, I discovered the captivating realm of data science. Armed with skills in Python, Rstudio, SQL, and more, I&amp;rsquo;ve delved into the realms of Predictive Modeling, Data Visualization, and Machine Learning. My journey has led me to libraries like NumPy, Pandas, and PyTorch, and I&amp;rsquo;ve embraced coding languages like Python, JavaScript, and Java.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
